<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncertainty Quantification | Himanshu Sharma</title>
    <link>https://himscipy.github.io/tag/uncertainty-quantification/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://himscipy.github.io/tag/uncertainty-quantification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Uncertainty Quantification</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Himanshu Sharma 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://himscipy.github.io/images/icon_hubbf93ac11c8082ceecfc59197d660a4d_16666_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Uncertainty Quantification</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/tag/uncertainty-quantification/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Neural Networks Distributed Training Performance Analysis at Scale</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-bnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-bnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayesian neural Networks (BNNs) are a promising method of obtaining statistical uncertainties for
neural network predictions but with a higher computational overhead which can limit their practical
usage. This work explores the use of high performance computing with distributed training to address
the challenges of training BNNs at scale. We present a performance and scalability comparison of
training the VGG-16 and Resnet-18 models on a Cray-XC40 cluster. We demonstrate that network
pruning can speed up inference without accuracy loss and provide an open source software package,
BPrune to automate this pruning. For certain models we find that pruning up to 80% of the network
results in only a 7.0% loss in accuracy. With the development of new hardware accelerators for Deep
Learning, BNNs are of considerable interest for benchmarking performance. This analysis of training
a BNN at scale outlines the limitations and benefits compared to a conventional neural network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indoor Air Quality Sensor Placement Accounting for Airflow Uncertainty </title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-sensorplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 19:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-sensorplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensors in buildings are used for a wide variety of applications such as monitoring air quality, contaminants, indoor temperature, and relative humidity. These are used for accessing and ensuring indoor air quality, and also for ensuring safety in the event of chemical and biological attacks. It follows that optimal placement of sensors become important to accurately monitor contaminant levels in the indoor environment. However, contaminant transport inside the indoor environment is governed by the indoor flow conditions which are affected by various uncertainties associated with the building systems including occupancy and boundary fluxes. Therefore, it is important to account for all associated uncertainties while designing the sensor layout.The transfer operator based framework provides an effective way to identify optimal placement of sensors. Previous work has been limited to sensor placements under deterministic scenarios. In this work we extend the transfer operator based approach for optimal sensor placement while accounting for building systems uncertainties. The methodology provides a probabilistic metric to gauge coverage under uncertain conditions. We illustrate the capabilities of the framework with examples exhibiting boundary flux uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
