<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy Simulation Tools | Himanshu Sharma</title>
    <link>https://himscipy.github.io/tag/energy-simulation-tools/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://himscipy.github.io/tag/energy-simulation-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Energy Simulation Tools</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Himanshu Sharma 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 11:00:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://himscipy.github.io/images/icon_hubbf93ac11c8082ceecfc59197d660a4d_16666_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Energy Simulation Tools</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/tag/energy-simulation-tools/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Fidelity Data Surrogates for Enhancing Co-Simulation Capabilities of Energy Simulation Tools</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/talk/my-talk-simbuild2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 11:00:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/talk/my-talk-simbuild2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indoor Air Quality Sensor Placement Accounting for Airflow Uncertainty </title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-sensorplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 19:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-sensorplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensors in buildings are used for a wide variety of applications such as monitoring air quality, contaminants, indoor temperature, and relative humidity. These are used for accessing and ensuring indoor air quality, and also for ensuring safety in the event of chemical and biological attacks. It follows that optimal placement of sensors become important to accurately monitor contaminant levels in the indoor environment. However, contaminant transport inside the indoor environment is governed by the indoor flow conditions which are affected by various uncertainties associated with the building systems including occupancy and boundary fluxes. Therefore, it is important to account for all associated uncertainties while designing the sensor layout.The transfer operator based framework provides an effective way to identify optimal placement of sensors. Previous work has been limited to sensor placements under deterministic scenarios. In this work we extend the transfer operator based approach for optimal sensor placement while accounting for building systems uncertainties. The methodology provides a probabilistic metric to gauge coverage under uncertain conditions. We illustrate the capabilities of the framework with examples exhibiting boundary flux uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surrogate Modeling for Integrating High-Fidelity Data with Energy Simulations Tools</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-atticsurrogate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-atticsurrogate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attic specific energy modeling tools are used by engineers and researchers to evaluate the impact of different design features, products, and materials systems on an attic&amp;rsquo;s energy, thermal, and hygrothermal performance. These frameworks and their simulation component models have been carefully validated over the last 40–50 years. A fundamental assumption in these modeling tools is that the air within the attic is well mixed. However, various experimental and numerical studies have shown that the flow inside a triangular attic is not well mixed and an asymmetrical heating of enclosure can develop flow instabilities. Under these flow regimes the calculation of interior convective fluxes using empirical correlations can be error prone. To investigate the impact of this assumption on the performance of a benchmark attic problem, we develop a coupling approach between the Fraunhofer Attic Thermal Model (FATM) and computational fluid dynamics (CFD). Instead of directly coupling a CFD solver to FATM, this paper presents an offline surrogate modeling coupling strategy. The generalized method established in this paper allows for future extension of the approach for different attic geometries, as well as whole building simulations. The work flow uses open-source tools for constructing the surrogate and making it easily integrable with any commercial/non-commercial whole building or attic simulation framework. Since the majority of the computations are moved offline, this approach provides substantial computational speedup during online simulations in comparison to earlier coupling approaches. An additional benefit of the approach is the surrogate can also be used for flow visualization inside the attic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
