<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning | Himanshu Sharma</title>
    <link>https://himscipy.github.io/tag/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://himscipy.github.io/tag/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine Learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Himanshu Sharma 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://himscipy.github.io/images/icon_hubbf93ac11c8082ceecfc59197d660a4d_16666_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/tag/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Deep Learning with Computational Fluid Dynamics Solvers</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-tensorflowmachinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-tensorflowmachinelearning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reynolds-averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS) equations for steady-state assessment of incompressible turbulent flows remain the workhorse for practical computational fluid dynamics (CFD) applications, and improvements in speed or accuracy have the potential to affect a diverse range of sectors. We introduce a machine learning framework for the acceleration of RANS to predict steady-state turbulent eddy viscosities, given the initial conditions. This surrogate model for the turbulent eddy viscosity is assessed for parametric interpolation, while numerically solving for the pressure and velocity equations to steady-state, thus representing a framework that is hybridized with machine learning. We achieve accurate steady-state results with a significant reduction in solution time when compared to those obtained by the Spalart-Allmaras one-equation model. Most notably the proposed methodology allows for considerably larger relaxation factors for the steady-state velocity and pressure solvers. Our assessments are made for a backward-facing step with considerable mesh anisotropy and separation to represent a practical CFD application. For test experiments with varying inlet velocity conditions, we see time-to-solution reductions around a factor of 5. Similar results are obtained for a surrogate modeling strategy that generalizes across varying step heights. The proposed framework represents an excellent opportunity for the rapid exploration of large parameter spaces that prove prohibitive when utilizing turbulence closure models with multiple coupled partial differential equations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Neural Networks Distributed Training Performance Analysis at Scale</title>
      <link>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-bnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://himscipy.github.io/project/my-project-bnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayesian neural Networks (BNNs) are a promising method of obtaining statistical uncertainties for
neural network predictions but with a higher computational overhead which can limit their practical
usage. This work explores the use of high performance computing with distributed training to address
the challenges of training BNNs at scale. We present a performance and scalability comparison of
training the VGG-16 and Resnet-18 models on a Cray-XC40 cluster. We demonstrate that network
pruning can speed up inference without accuracy loss and provide an open source software package,
BPrune to automate this pruning. For certain models we find that pruning up to 80% of the network
results in only a 7.0% loss in accuracy. With the development of new hardware accelerators for Deep
Learning, BNNs are of considerable interest for benchmarking performance. This analysis of training
a BNN at scale outlines the limitations and benefits compared to a conventional neural network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
